Ahmed Saber Fathy

Desouk, Kafr El Sheikh, Egypt (GMT+2)

J +20 120 861 1892

✓ <u>ahmed0saber33@gmail.com</u>

• https://github.com/ahmed0saber

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmed0saber/

Summary

Hello there, My name is Ahmed Saber, I'm a React.js Frontend Web Developer who has 2+ years of work experience in the industry of frontend web development, I enjoy building everything with JavaScript.

In this duration, I have learned a lot of technologies, created many cool websites, collaborated with great developers and contributed to open source projects. So I'm always seeking to have an opportunity that matches my skills, to make the best use of all what I have learned.

Skills

> HTML5

> JavaScript (ES6)

> jQuery

> SASS

> Redux & Redux toolkit

> Electron.js

> CSS3

> JSON

> Bootstrap

> React.js

> Next.js

> Socket.io

Languages

> Arabic - native

> English - conversational

Experience

> Valinteca - Remote
Mid-Level Frontend Developer - Full Time
Feb 2023 - Present
Frontend Web Developer - Full Time
April 2022 - Feb 2023

> Orizon PR & Marketing - Remote Frontend Web Developer - Freelance Ian 2023 - Present

> Across The Globe (ATG) - Remote React JS Developer - Internship April 2022 - May 2022

Education

> Bachelor of Science - Physics Department
Kafr El Sheikh university - Kafr El Sheikh - Egypt
Undergraduate, 2019 - 2023

Projects

> My Portfolio

That's my personal website where I show my skills and projects.

- Built with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, JSON, React.js
- View at https://ahmed0saber.onrender.com

> XO Online

XO game where you can play vs easy or hard bot, vs local or online player, chat with people, invite them, win more games and rank up.

- Built with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, Socket.io
- View at https://xo-online.herokuapp.com

> TestMode

A website where you can test your skills in some technologies related to programming and get certified.

- Built with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, JSON, React.js, Next.js
- View at https://testmode.vercel.app

Community Activities

> Speaker

Panimalar Institute Of Technology, March 2023

> Technical Content Translator

freeCodeCamp, Jan 2023 - Present

> JavaScript Instructor

Az-SENCS, March 2022 - June 2022

Certificates

- > Triplebyte Advanced level in General Coding Logic & Front-end & React
- Verify at https://triplebyte.com/tb/ahmed-saber-otjngy3/certificate
- > MaharaTech Certified JavaScript Developer & ReactJS Developer & Front-End Developer
- Verify at https://github.com/ahmed0saber/certifications/tree/main/maharatech
- > Pluralsight Expert level in HTML & CSS & JavaScript & Bootstrap & React | Proficient level in ES6 & TypeScript
- Verify at https://app.pluralsight.com/profile/ahmed-saber-4a
- > TestDome Top 10% in HTML & CSS & Bootstrap & JavaScript & React & SQL
- Verify at https://github.com/ahmed0saber/certifications/tree/main/TestDome